-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
本片内容以及字幕仅供学习交流
严禁用于商业途径
===我很反感那些===
使用别人字幕却删去
===译制人员信息===
的人或者组织
字幕译制&校对：yourtear@TLF
压制：yourtear@TLF
This door?
是这间吗？
This box or that box?
这个箱子还是那个啊？
Are they all for me?
这些都是给我的？
Cool. Thanks!
酷啊，谢谢
Hey, where are you going?
Hey, what are you doing?
嘿，你去哪儿了？
嘿，你要干什么？
Hey, open the door
Hey! What's going on?
嘿，把门开开！
嘿！怎么回事？
There is nothing, no name, no face
那儿什么都没有，没有名字，没有外貌
I was born into nothingness,
我被降临到虚无的世界
you could say I don't exist.
可以说，我从不存在
【私生子】
真棒，再来一次！
非常好，要不要再做一次？
Daddy, look what I can do!
爸，快瞧我现在做的！
Very Good!
非常好！
Hi!
嘿！
Hallo!
你好！
Could you help me?
I lost my goggles
能帮我一下吗？我的游泳镜掉了
Dad, look.
爸，快看
Great.
很好
They are down there in the deep wateg
but I can't dive that deep.
它掉深水区了，我潜不到那么深
Dad, you are not looking.
爸，你根本都没看
Of course I am.
噢，知道了
- Would you help me?  - Yeah sure.
- 能帮我吗？    - 好的，可以
Lotte, wait here in the shallow wateg
I'll be right back.
洛特，在这浅水区等着，我马上就回来
So, where are your goggles?
大概掉在哪儿？
Down there.
这下面
There you go.
给
Thanks!
谢谢！
No problem!
没关系！
Would you go on the slide with me.
I get scared on my own.
跟我一起去滑梯吧，我一个人不敢滑
No way.
不行
Or we could play 'animal jumping',
或者我们去玩“动物跳水”
I'll jump into the water and pretend to be an animal
and you have to guess what I am.
我学一种动物姿势跳水，你来猜是什么动物
I am here with my daughter.
我是带女儿来的
Your daughter sucks at doing the handstand.
你女儿玩的那个水中倒立姿势不对
She can't do it at all!
她做那么差劲
What are you talking about?
你在胡说些什么？
What the..., Hey, stop this bullshit!
Leave my daughter alone!
嘿！别做这样的傻事了！别来烦我的女儿！
Lotte, come on... let's get something to drink.
洛特，我们去喝点东西吧
Asshole!
混蛋
Mrs. Heine?
海纳女士？
I am one of Nicolas's friends.
We play soccer together
我是尼库拉斯的朋友，我们一起踢球的
Nicolas isn't home.
尼库拉斯他不在
I know... but I borrowed him my knee guards,
我知道…可我把自己的护腿板借给他了
and just wanted to ask, if I could get them back.
然后我想问问能不能拿回来
I need them for tomorrow's game.
Otherwise, I won't be allowed to play.
我明天比赛要用的，要不然就不能上场了
Come in,
进来吧
but please take off your shoes.
请把鞋脱了
I have an appointment with detective Becker or Egger.
我要找贝克尔探长或者叫艾格尔？
Decker chief superintendent Decker.
戴克尔，总警司戴克尔
You are standing on my foot.
您踩着我的脚了
Oh, I am sorry.
额，对不起
Give me your umbrella!
把您的伞给我吧！
And get me some rubber boots.
再去帮我找一双胶鞋来
Do you have any idea of when Nicolas will be back?
您觉得尼库拉斯什么时候会回来？
Our team would collect some money,in order to help out.
要是有必要的话，我们球队可以捐点钱的
That's very kind,
but I'am afraid ransom won't help.
谢谢好意，不过我觉得钱起不到作用
The knee guards,they must be in the cupboard, somewhere.
护腿板应该是在柜子里面
I didn't know that Nicolas is still
playing with dolls.
我之前还不知道尼库拉斯还在玩毛绒娃娃
Not Friedolin, the rabbit, please don't touch him!
别碰福利多林，这兔娃娃
Hello, I'm Friedolin.
I am cold and I am all alone.
你好，我是福利多林
我好冷，而且一直一个人
Put him back! Put him back!
把它放回去！把它放回去！
Do you know, who I am?
知道我是谁吗？
I think, it's time for you to leave.
我觉得你该走了！
Mrs. Meinert?
麦纳特女士？
Decker, we talked on the phone.
戴克尔，阿历克山大·戴克尔
我们之前通过电话
Or shoud I say doctor Meinert.
我是不是该叫你麦纳特博士？
Meinert is fine.
叫我麦纳特就行
Thank's for coming down so quickly.
很感谢能如此迅速赶来
I think we can save the compliments.
我觉得我们可以跳过这些恭维之词了
If I understood correctly, we are pushed for time.
要是我理解得没错的话，目前我们应该争分夺秒
Who was that?
刚才是谁？
Nobody.
没啥
The boy was last seen when leaving
school after his sixth lesson.
这男孩最后一次被目击是在他上完第六节课后放学回家
He never arrived at home.
We are still searching his way to school.
然后却再没出现，我们仍旧在他家与学校沿路搜查
Do you know what mouldy sandwiches,
like them ones mean?
您知道这些发霉的三明治意味着什么吗？
This syndrome is almost exclusively found in boys.
这种情况一般只在男孩子身上出现
They don't want to eat their sandwich,
but they are unable to throw it away.
他们不愿意吃给他们准备的三明治
但又不知道要把这东西从书包里扔掉
So the sandwiches start moulding...
just like a bad conscience.
所以这些三明治就会在书包里发霉，变质…
就好象坏情绪一样
Do you have kids, Mrs Meinert?
您有孩子吗，麦纳特女士？
I don't get along with kids.
我跟孩子处不好
Good afternoon ladies and gentleman,
may I see you tickets please?
下午好，女士们先生们，请大家出示一下车票
Are you also travelling without a ticket?
你也是逃票吗？
May I?
让我一下？
I don't mind if you need to piss,
unless you need to go for a shit,
你如果要小便，我不介意的，除非你想要上大号
that would be pretty uncool.
那就太扫兴了
Did that hurt?
穿这耳洞疼吗？
Are you pretending to be on an 'emo trip'?
Because I am talking too much, or what?
不想搭理我还是咋的？
You look propper gay.
But you have nice eyes.
你看起来更像是同性恋
不过眼睛很漂亮
I need to get out of here.
我得出去了
Cute.
可爱
Pussy.
娘炮
What are you doing there?
你躺这儿干嘛？
Oh, I am sorry...
I was just thinking.
哦，我正在想……
很抱歉…
Don't worry I'll take care of that!
没事，我来弄这些！
Maybe you could help me.
I am looking for something personal from your son.
或许您能帮我一下，我想找一些您孩子的私人物品
Something that was important to him.
一些对于他来说很重要的物件
The football.
那个足球
Do you have something more personal.
有没有更私密一点的
It's signed by all players.
这上面有全队球员签名的
What about this rabbit?
这只兔娃娃怎样？
Lost
不见了
Please take off your shoes inside the house
下次进屋前请脱鞋
Mum?
妈？
Mum!
妈！
Get up! Come on, get up!
来！快点，起来！
Mathilda, why aren't you at school?
马蒂尔达，你怎么没去上学？
It's half past seven.
都已经六点半了
Did you smoke?
你抽烟了？
Come on, get up.
快，起来吧！
It's all right mum.
没事的，妈
I don't want to.
我不想洗
But I don't want to.
我真不想啊
But you have to.
你必须得洗
The water is cold.
这水太凉了
Look, I made it warmer
瞧，我把它调热了
But it's still cold.
可还是很凉
I made some Spaghetti for you,
you like eating them, don't you?
我给你做了意大利面条
你喜欢吃的，是不是啊？
I saw it, thanks.
我看到了，谢谢
I am sick.
我好难受
Mama you have to take a shower
妈妈，你得冲一下
The water is cold.
水太凉了
But I just made it warmer.
但我刚已经调热了呢
But it's still cold.
但还是很凉
Mum, you smell of piss.
妈，你身上一股尿骚味
How are you talking to me?!
你怎么说话呢！
You shouldn't talk in this way
with your mother.
你不该跟你妈妈这个样子说话的
I am your mum.
我毕竟是你妈
I am sorry.
对不起
The water is cold.
水是凉的
I made it warmer
我已经又调热了
AUAAAAA. IT'S BOILING!
啊…好冷！
How was school?
学校里还好吗？
Your mother asked you something.
你妈在问你话呢
Would you please turn of the TV
At least, as long as we're having dinner.
能把电视关上吗？至少别在吃饭时候看
TV: Somewhere out there,
there is someone who knows where our son is.
肯定有人知道我们的儿子在哪里
We beg you, don't hurt our child.
我们求你了，别伤害孩子
Did you hear what your mother said?
没听见你妈刚才说的吗？
We do whatever you want,
but please give us a sign of life.
我们可以答应你的任何要求
但请告知我们他的音讯
Show us that our son is all right.
让我们知道我们的儿子现在没事
Nicolas is a good boy...
尼库拉斯是一个好孩子…
he loves playing football and he is very popular with his friends.
他喜欢踢足球，在朋友圈里很受欢迎
Nicolas loves his rabbits
and cares about them attentively.
尼库拉斯喜欢他的宠物兔…
把它们照料得非常好
I am sorry, I can't do this.
我无法继续，抱歉
Hello?
你好？
喂？
Hello. Is anybody there?
喂，是不是有人？
喂，那边是不是有人？
Don't go away. Hey!
别走…嘿！
Mrs. Meinert?
麦纳特女士？
I have a message for you.
这是给您的
Please give a call! Max
[请给我电话！  - 马克斯]
If this gentleman calls again,
tell him that I've left.
要是这位先生来电，就告诉他我出门了
Thank you!
谢谢
Yes?
喂？
Hello Mrs Meinert, it's me.
We have a sign of life.
麦纳特女士，是我
我们得到孩子的讯息了
The mating dance of the humpback
wales can last for many hours
座头鲸的交配舞蹈可以持续好几个小时
and is often accompanied by complex signing.
而且经常发出复杂的声音
In order to mate, the wales swim tightly
along side one another
为了交配，鲸鱼会紧贴着另一头一起游泳
mainly upright, while their bellies
are touching and they nibble
几乎完全笔直，然后它们的腹部会相互触碰
on each others mouth.
而它们还会轻咬对方的嘴巴
Mathilda, would you come to the front please?
玛蒂尔达，请到讲台上来
Mathilda!
玛蒂尔达！
Please explain, how mammal fertilisation works.
请解释一下哺乳动物是如何受精的
And take your hair out of your mouth, please!
请不要咬你的头发了
Where does the fertilisation take place?
受精是在哪里发生的？
In the cunt.
在屄里
We found the video on many of our student's mobiles.
在我校许多学生的手机里发现了这段视频
It's like approaching dogs.
Just don't show them that you are scared.
就好似在跟狗狗接触，别让他们感觉到你在害怕
That's my seat.
这是我的位置
Hi!
嗨！
Hello!
哈喽！！
Thank you.
谢谢
First of all, I am asking you all to turn off your mobile phones.
首先，我想要求大家先把手机都关掉
If I hear one of them ring,
I am going to collect them all.
如果听到一声铃响，我就会没收你们所有的手机
Well, this is Mrs. Meinert from the police.
这位是警局来的麦纳特女士
She would like to ask you a few questions.
她将会问大家几个问题
Which one of you has seen the video of Nicolas.
你们中有谁看过了尼库拉斯的那段视频
Louder!
大点声！
Which one of you has seen the video of Nicolas,
the boy in the cellar
你们中有谁看过了尼库拉斯的那段视频？
那个被关在地下室的男生
No one will get into trouble if they have seen it.
I watched it myself.
没人会因为看过那段视频而惹上麻烦的，我也看了
I watched it. A friend sent it to me.
我看了，一个朋友发给我看的
And what did you think, when you saw it?
当你看到它的时候，你是怎么想的？
The bunny was cute.
兔娃娃很可爱
I, I also watched the video,
I thought it was horrorifying.
我…我也看了，我觉得太阴暗恐怖了
I thought, it was funny.
我认为比较有意思
That is not funny.
怎么能觉得这个有意思呢？
It clapped when he fell.
谁要是喜欢就鼓掌呗
I want to see the victim.
我想要见他
Who else has seen the video?
还有谁看过这视频？
Is it real?
是真的吗？
Yes, the video is real.
没错，是真实的
We are going to have one-on-one interviews
with all of you now.
我将会跟你们每个人单独谈话
请给你们父母电话…
Please let your parents know that
you are going to be late.
告诉他们你们今天会晚点放学
I want to see the victim,
and I want an ice-cream.
我要见那个受害者，而且还要个冰淇淋
Mrs. Schockenhoff.
Mrs. SCHOCKENHOOOFFFF!!!
舒肯霍夫女士，舒肯霍夫女士！
Yes, please.
什么事？
Wait for me after school.
放学后等我
I need to pee.
我想要上厕所
Name and grade, please!
告诉我姓名还有年级
Nine B.
九年级B班
Name?
名字呢？
I don't have a name.
我没有名字
Everybody has a name.
每个人都有名字
Not me.
可我没
Don't you like your name?
你不喜欢自己的名字吗？
Your name is Claudia Meinert, right.
你的名字是克劳迪娅·麦纳特，对不？
Yea.
对
Do you have a second name?
你有小名吗？
Hanne, Hannelore. And you?
汉娜，汉娜罗拉，你呢？
Did your father used to call you like that?
Hanne?
你的爸爸会那么叫你吗？汉娜？
Why don't you just pick a name,
one that you like?
你为何不选一个你自己喜欢的名字呢？
You don't choose names, names are given to you.
名字不是自己选的，是别人给的！
Parents give their children names.
父母会给他们的孩子起名字
It says here, your name is
这上面写了你的名字叫…
I don't have a name.
我没名字
Well, did you know the boy from the video?
好吧，你认识视频里的那个男生吗？
We play in the same club.
我们在同一家俱乐部踢球
And did you ever fight with him.
那你有没有跟他打过架
He is very popular
他很招人喜欢的
I asked you,if you ever had a fight with him.
我问你的是，你有没有跟他打过架
Do you know anybody who has had a fight with him.
或者你知不知道有谁跟他打过架
Like I said, he is very popular.
就像我说的，他很招人喜欢
Maybe a bit too popular
或许是因为太招人喜欢了呢
It's says here that you are highly talented,
you skipped the seventh grade.
上面说你智商很高，直接把七年级跳过了
It's not easy?
挺不容易吧？
What?
什么？
Making friends.
交朋友
I have other interests.
我有别的兴趣
For example?
比如？
Girls, fashion, music.
May I go now?
女孩，时尚，音乐！我能走了吗？
And where exactly is your victim supposed to be?
那个受害者人呢？
Hey, what is this shit?
嘿，这算是哪一出？
Switch the lights back on!
快把灯打开！
Hello?
喂？
I am here.
我在这儿
Switch the lights on immediately!
快点开灯啊！
I am right behind you.
我就在你身后
Is the victim in here too?
受害者也在这儿？
Yes.
是的
When are you going to make it happen?
你打算什么时候做？
Kill the victim?
什么时候杀他？
I have a special plan with him beforehand.
我接下来还有一个特别计划
What's that?
什么计划？
He is going to be my birthday present.
我将会是我的生日礼物
I want to watch, when you do it.
你杀他的时候，我想看
I want to be there, when you do it.
你杀他的时候，我要在场
I want to watch, when somebody is dying.
我想看着人死去的样子
Mrs. Schweizer?
施瓦茨女士？
My name is Claudia Meinert.
我的名字是克劳迪娅·麦纳特
Did something happen to my husband?
我丈夫出什么状况了？
Your husband is fine.
您的丈夫没事
I have a few questions regarding your son.
我想问几个关于您儿子的问题
I imagined him to be much taller.
我的想象中，他个子更高点
Come over here!
来这边！
What's the matter?
怎么啦？
You wanted to see him.
Now you saw him.
你想看他，现在你已经看到了
I thought we were going do something together today.
我以为我们俩今天会一起做点什么的呢
Also, I still want my ice cream.
而且我还没吃到冰淇淋呢
You will get your ice cream.
会给你吃的
Asshole.
混蛋
Give me your watch!
把你的手表给我！
I asked you to give me your watch!
让你把表给我！你的表！
YOUR WATCH!!!
给我你的手表！
May try yours?
能尝一下你的吗？
Tomorrow is fun fair
I want you to take me there.
明天有游乐园，我想让你带我去
No time.
没工夫
Else, I will tell everybody where your victim is.
那我就告诉所有人
If you do that?
要是你敢那么做…
What then?
那就怎样？
Then you'll never see someone dying.
那你就永远看不到人是怎么死的
I bet, you don't dare to do it anyway.
反正我赌你没胆那么做
Tomorrow at five at the crawler.
明天五点钟在旋转飞爪前面
Is that a date.
算是约会吗？
Cool.
爽
See you tomorrow.
明天见
Come on you have to eat something.
来吃点东西吧
I am not hungry.
我不饿
Shall I make you a salad.
要不给你去拌个色拉？
I don't understand how you can eat at all.
真不明白你竟然还能吃得进
Are you Nicolas Dad?
你是尼库拉斯的爸爸吗？
I promised Nicolas to feed his rabbits
while he is away.
我答应尼库拉斯，在他不在家的时候帮他喂兔子的
Moritz, Finny, Schnuffy and Carl.
莫里茨，芬妮，史努飞还有卡尔
When did you talk to Nicolas?
你什么时候跟尼库拉斯谈的？
May I come in?
我能进屋吗？
Sure, come in.
当然，请进
Weren't you here yesterday?
你昨天已经来过的吧？
What do you want?
你想干什么？
He claims that he spoke to Nicolas.
他说他跟尼库拉斯聊过
Oh, did I interrupt your dinner?
Should I come back later?
是不是打搅到你们吃晚饭了？
那我过会儿再来吧？
When exactly did you talk to Nicolas?
你究竟是什么时候跟尼库拉斯说话的？
May I have something to drink?
可以给我点喝的吗？
Milk, if you have any.
有没有牛奶？
That is Nicolas seat.
那是尼库拉斯的位置
Please explain us in detail,
when exactly you spoke to Nicolas.
请确切告诉我们，你是什么时候跟尼库拉斯谈话的
Would you make me a sandwich?
再给我切块面包吧？
Out! OUT!
出去！出去！
Anja, wait! Wait!
安雅，等等！等等！
Oh, I am sorry.
额，非常抱歉
It's late, my parents are
waiting for me with dinner.
已经不早了，我爸妈还在等我吃饭呢
Where did you get this watch?
这手表是哪里来的？
I want her to make me a sandwiche, with salami.
她应该给我准备面包的，要带火腿片的
And now, you are going to tell me
where you got this damn watch from!
告诉我，你是从哪里得到这块手表的！
I want her to make it!
我是让她给我！
I know it's late, but...
我知道现在不早了，不过…
My wife is already asleep.
Maybe it's better you come back tomorrow.
我爱人已经睡了，你最好明天再来
I just wanted to ask if you know this boy.
我只是想问问你们是不是认识这个男生
No!
不！
Five minutes. Give me five minutes.
五分钟！ 就只要给我五分钟！
After that, you can do anything you want with me.
五分钟之后，你让我做什么都行
He said, he knows where Nicolas is.
He's got his watch.
他说他知道尼库拉斯在什么地方，他有孩子的手表
Open this door immediately.
Open the doog right now! RIGHT NOW!
把门打开！立刻把门打开！马上！
Morning.
早安
I have a new boyfriend.
我交了新男友
Didn 't you want to buy milk?
你没有买牛奶回来吗？
I think, I am in love.
我想我是爱上他了
We want to go to the fair tonight.
Do you have any money?
我们今晚要去游乐园，你有钱吗？
You know how it works?
你知道应该怎么用的吧？
I would be a shit grandma, you know that.
我可不想现在就当外婆，你知道的
Thank you.
谢谢
I am expecting company tonight,
would be cool, if you could stay in your room.
我今晚还有访客，最好你就待在自己的房间
Yeah!
好！
I am a child, I am incapable of crime,
whatever I do.
我还是小孩，无法指控我的，不管我干了什么
I know the law.
我懂法
So, I can go now?
我现在可以走了吗？
This says, your birthday is in three days.
上面说，你三天后就要过生日了
You will turn fourteen and that means
you will no longer be freed of crime.
那时候你就十四岁了，也就意味着不会被免予指控
In three days, Nicolas is dead.
三天之后，尼库拉斯就死了
I am tired, may I go now?
我累了，可以先走吗？
We can't do anything, he knows that.
他知道我们做不了什么
We will claim charge against the father.
我们会起诉他父亲
Bring the boy home!
Clarify if the parents comply their fiduciary duty.
带这孩子回家！向他们父母阐明监护义务
We will be observing him, day and night.
我们会日夜监控他的
What the fuck.
他在干啥！
Our Hanne is pregnant.
我们的汉娜怀孕了
Give it back!
还给我！
Did you already know, our Hanne is pregnant?
你知道吗，这位汉娜怀孕了
That's enough!
闹够了！走吧
Do you already have name for the little one?
给小宝宝起好名字了没？
Or is it going to be a little girl,
a little Hanne?
或者是个小女孩呢……一个小汉娜？
Will you ride the crawler with me?
带我一起坐旋转飞爪吧？
Just one time... I get scared on my own.
就一次…我一个人不敢坐
I am here with my children.
我是带我孩子一起来的
Otherwise, I am going to tell my mother
that you touched me.
不然我就告诉我妈你摸我
I did what?
我啥？
You touched my tits.
你摸了我的胸
Are you nuts?
你神经病啊？
Just one round. One little bitty round.
就坐一轮，就那么一小会儿
Get off!
一边去！
Asshole.
混蛋
Sabine Meissner Seventy, four years of age,
she fell in her apartment,
萨比娜·麦斯纳，七十四岁，摔倒在自己的公寓
three weeks later the neighbours complained about the smell.
三周之后，邻居抱怨她屋子有异味传出
Blistering on the lips,
mucosal skin dried out and lacerated,
嘴唇起泡，粘膜层干裂
the tonsils inflamed.
扁桃体发炎
That's how somebody looks, who died of thirst.
那些被渴死的人看上去就是这副样子
I know it from the TV
我在电视上见过
Well then, touch hen
那行，你摸摸看
It's just a dead body.
尸体而已
Feels like a cold apple, and now?
感觉像是冰过的苹果，现在呢？
If Nicolas dies, he will feel the same.
要是尼库拉斯死了，摸起来的感觉也是一样
And you will feel guilty for your entire life,
because you were unable to save him.
然后你的余生都将会因为没能救出他而自责
His grades are good,
we have no problems with him.
他学习成绩很好，我们跟他也没什么问题
He is one of the best students in his year,
at least in written work.
他是他们班上最好的学生之一，至少从考试成绩来看
I think, you didn't really get my point.
Your son committed a serious crime.
我不知道你们有没有领会我的意思
你们的儿子现在涉及刑事犯罪
Are you sure,
I mean do you have any evidence?
您确定吗？我是说，您有证据吗？
He confessed.
他亲口承认了
Do you mind if I smoke?
不介意我抽烟吧？
Not in the house, Cora please!
请别在屋里抽烟，科拉！
Has your son changed at all recently?
你们有没有感觉到孩子近段时间有什么变化？
How were we supposed to?
He barely even speaks to us.
怎么感觉？他几乎不跟我们交流
That's a change, don't you think?
这就是一种变化，你不觉得吗？
We thought, it's the age.
我们还以为，青春期都这样
Your son no longer answers to his name.
I think that's not normal, don't you?
你们的孩子已经不愿意提及他的名字了
我觉得这有点不寻常，是不是？
Sammy, would you please hand me my coat?
萨米，能帮我把外套拿来吗？
I am sorry,could you please repeat your question?
不好意思，您能再重复一下刚才的问题吗？
If your son doesn't answer to his own name,
to what does he answer then?
要是您儿子不理睬自己的名字，那他会应什么？
Nothing. Just: Hey you.
没什么，就是：喂，你！
Do you remember any triggeg a fight maybe?
有什么矛盾起因吗？
He just stopped talking to us.
他就是那样停止跟我们交流了
It got worse last year
去年开始更糟糕了
He used to work things out by himself.
他总是自己解决自己的问题
As I said, it got worse last year.
就像我说的，去年开始变糟糕的
I can't force my child to talk to me.
我肯定也无法强迫孩子跟我交流
But you try it over and over again.
但你一直在不断地说
Yes, unlike you, I try to talk to my son,
that's right.
没错，反正不像你，我试图跟我儿子交流，那很正常
Do you still have physical contact with your son?
你们还有没有肢体语言上的交流？
Touching, hugs, cuddles...
安抚，拥抱，接近…
He is thirteen.
I don't get your question.
他已经十三岁了，我不明白您的意思
If I understand you right,
要是我理解的没错的话
your son has been socially completely isolated
for more than one year now.
您孩子已经至少有一年时间，从他的社会关系中脱离了
That's right you could say that.
没错，可以那么说
No, that's not right.
Only recently he completed an internship
不，不是那样的，最近他还去做了实习呢
a student internship in the youth well-fare office.
在青年福利局的学生实习
That's kind of social, isn't it.
那算是一种社交活动吧？
Does that mean it's all my fault?
难道现在都觉得是我的责任？
This isn't about fault.
现在不是谁的责任的问题
What then?
那要咋样？
I think, you are hiding something from me.
我感觉您有在隐瞒什么
Nicolas?
尼库拉斯？
What do you want from me?
你想要我做什么？
Will this be one of this: Show me your room
and I will tell you who you are thing?
现在你要说的是不是：
带我去看你的房间，然后我告诉你是谁
My self perception is disturbed.
你打搅到我自慰了
Would you please wait outside?
你能不能去外面等着？
Nietzsche said: We do not accuse nature of being
immoral if it sends us a thunderstorm.
尼采曾说过，即使大自然带给我们暴风雨
我们也不会去指责它的不道德
Why do we call a human being immoral if he kills.
No one is born evil.
要是有人杀了人，为何我们称之为邪恶？
没有人天生是邪恶的
So, it's society's fault or that of the parents?
那是社会的错，还是父母的错？
May I have one too?
能给我也来一支吗？
Nice lighten
打火机不错
I had it since I was twelve, pure brass,
you won't find this anymore today.
我十二岁的时候就得到它了，纯铜打造
现如今是找不到这样的货了
May I?
给我看看？
You're welcome!
给！
Did your father give it to you?
是你父亲送给你的？
No, I just found in somewhere,
and never lost it since.
不是，是我自己弄来的，然后就没丢弃过
Look at the lighter!
瞧这个打火机
I just want to answer your question.
我只想回答你的问题
Until now, I am nobody, just someone
that you have barely known for three days.
直到现在，我对于你来说
只不过是一个刚认识了三天的泛泛之辈
Look at the lighter!
你该看着这打火机的！
Now I am the one who broke your lighten
现在我则成为了弄坏你打火机的人
That has been my favourite lighter
for over forty years.
这是我最喜欢的打火机，跟了我四十年
The more it hurts you, the deeper our relationship.
伤得你越深，我们之间的关系也越深
You want to have a relationship with me,
and therefore you brake my lighter?
你想跟我建立关系，所以就弄坏了我的打火机？
If this is the only way to get in contact with you.
要是这是能跟你获得接触的唯一途径
Now you will never forget me.
现在你永远都不会忘记我了
No, this I'll never forget.
不，我永远不会忘记你的恶行
And that is his motive,
he want's a relationship with her at any cost.
这就是他的动机
他想不惜一切代价跟她建立起关系
If you would be a guy, I would smack you for that.
要是我再年轻几岁，我会因此而揍你的
I will buy you a new one.
我会给你再弄个新的来
I also know a Nietzsche saying...
我也知道尼采的一句话
The one who fights with monsters needs to be careful
跟恶魔战斗的时候，需要注意…
that he doesn't turn into a monster himself.
…不要让自己变成恶魔
Like I said, I'll get you an new one.
我说了，会给你弄个新的
May I ask you a personal question?
能问你一个私人问题吗？
Maybe another time.
还是下次吧
Fucking cold today.
今天真他妈冷啊
Coffee would be good.
有杯咖啡喝就好了
I'll go and check what's going on.
我去看看怎么回事
Nicolas.
尼库拉斯
Oh shit.
见鬼
Come I'll clean you.
来，我给你弄干净
You know, that happened to me once, too
知道吗，我也曾这样过
I woke up becausel had to pee so badly.
我被惊醒了，发现尿湿了一大片
And then?
然后呢？
I pissed the whole bed.
我几乎把整张床都尿透了
The next day it stank like.
第二天，它闻起来…
Like a pissed tramp.
像一个臭流浪汉
Right, like a fully pissed tramp.
没错，像一个满身尿骚的流浪汉
Come, we'll get you fresh clothes.
来，我给你弄干净的衣服来
Advertisement for telephone sex.
[色情电话的广告]
Our people are on it.
For now we can only wait.
我们的人在里面盯着，我们也只能等待
Anything new about the cellar?
有关于那地下室的线索吗？
A cellar without any windows,
every second cellar in town looks like this.
没有窗户的地下室，这城市有半数的地下室都这模样
Anything wrong?
怎么啦？
No.
没事
You looked at me strangely.
你看我的眼神好奇怪
I didn't look at you.
我没在看你
Sure, you looked at me strangely.
就有，你就是在奇怪地看着我
Here, some new games this is even adult rated.
给你几个新游戏，这个刚出的，甚至还有限制级的
I want to go home.
我想要回家
You can go home again,
when your mother does what I say.
要是你的妈妈按我说的做，你就能回家了
Where were you?  We had a date?
你去哪了？ 我们约好了的
No time.
没工夫
But for the victim you have time, or what?
但你却有时间去找那受害者玩，是不是？
His name is Nicolas.
他叫尼库拉斯
You are bleeding.
你受伤了
You are crazy, you know that?
你是神经病，知道吗？
Like I said, we are a perfect match.
所以我说咱们俩是天生一对
Can I crash at your place tonight?
我今晚能去你那睡吗？
No time.
没工夫
Isn't that the cop chick from school?
那个不是来过学校的女警察吗？
Do you want to go swimming?
有兴趣去游泳吗？
Yes.
好呀
Will you slide with me, I am scared alone.
跟我一起滑吧，我一个人害怕
Faster! Come on, faster!
快呀，快点！
I want an ice-cream.
我要吃冰淇淋
We have to talk.
我们得谈谈
Thanks.
谢谢
Anja.
安雅
Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢啦
Can you put some lotion on my back?
能给我的背上擦点油吗？
Also under the bikini!
从比基尼下面擦！
Mathilda, what do want to have for dinner?
- 你晚上想要吃什么？
- 无所谓
What's your favourite dish?
你最爱吃什么？
Spaghetti Bolognese.
But real Bolognese, not the canned stuff.
番茄牛肉酱意面
不过要真正的牛肉酱，而不是罐头货
Can you make that?
你会做吗？
Yes.
恩
HELLO! HELP! HELP!
有人吗！救命！救命！
HELLO! Is there anybody out there?
喂！外面有人吗？
HELLO! HELP! HELP!
你好！救命！救命！
That's really yummy.
Are you not hungry?
真的很好吃，你不饿吗？
We eat all together!
我们大家一起吃！
I am not hungry.
我不饿
I want you to eat.
我想让你吃
You still have to ask how school was.
你还得问我们在学校里过得怎么样
How was school?
在学校里怎么样？
Good.
很好
We are eating!
我们吃饭！
These are the best Spaghetti ever
May I have some more?
这是我吃过的最好吃的意面
我能再吃一点吗？
What is this about?
这又算是哪一出？
I am hungry
我饿了
But you are not invited.
可又没有邀请你
Either I get some of your Spaghetti...
要么让我吃点你的意大利面…
or I will tell the others
what yummy meal you have here.
要么我去告诉别人这儿屋子里面有好吃的
Which others?
什么别人？
Would you hand me the sauce, please?
帮我把肉酱递一下吧？
I talked to you parents.
They want you to come home after dinner.
我跟你父母说过了
他们想让你晚饭之后就回家
I stay here for the night.
我晚上还想要在这儿
We stay here for the night.
There are pigs outside everywhere.
我们在这儿过夜，外面到处是警察
You are under age, that's the law.
你还未成年，法律就这么规定的
Unless we all stay here for the night.
除非我们大家都留在这儿
The sauce. Please!
我要肉酱！
Mathilda Herwick, mother on welfare,
single parent, alcohol.
玛蒂尔达·海尔维克，母亲在领救济，单身，酗酒
Father?
父亲呢？
Died, car accident,
when the kid was three.
死了，车祸，那时孩子三岁
Did he say what he wants?
他有说过想要什么吗？
The deal is: The police retreats in return
I will stay in the house.
跟他说好的是，警察全部撤走，我单独留在这儿
That's a shit deal.
这算是什么狗屁
He is going to bring it to an end
as long as he is incapable of crime.
在他失去未成年豁免权之前
肯定会对事情做一个了结的
Nicolas has twenty eight hours left.
所以尼库拉斯还有二十八小时
That's a beautiful pattern.
这个碗的造型真不错
Japanese cherry blossom,
the wedding gift of my parents, in law.
日本樱花，这是我公公婆婆给的结婚礼物
Where shall I put it?
该把它放哪里？
There inside the cupboard.
放那边柜子
How long for have you known your husband?
你认识你的丈夫有多久了？
We married when I was pregnant with Nicolas.
我们是在我怀了尼库拉斯之后结的婚
And before Raphael,was there any one else in your life.
除了拉斐尔，你之前有过其他男人吗？
I want to feed the rabbits, they are hungry too.
我要喂兔子，它们也饿了
There.
那儿
You didn't answer my question.
你还没回答我的问题呢
I guess, that's none of your business.
我觉得那不关你的事
There is a mistake.
Fiftysix divided by eight is seven not six.
这儿做错了，56除以8等于7，而不是6
56除以8等于7，而不是6
No, the eight isn't wrong,
the six is.
不是，这个八没错，而是六错了
Fortyeight divided by eight is six.
Two times six is?
48除以8等于6，6乘以2等于？
Six.
六
Six times two is twelve.
六乘以二等于十二
Three times four is?
三乘以四等于？
Three times four
Three times four is?
三乘以四，三乘以四等于？
Six.
六
Six times two is twelve.
Three times four is?
六乘以二等于十二，三乘以四等于？
Six
六
Not six, twelve!
不是六，是十二！
Six, six, six
六，六，六，…
sex
性
Twelve, six times two is twelve.
十二，六乘以二等于十二
Six, point six six six.
六，六点六六六…
Sex.
性
Shall we play something?
我们来玩点什么吧？
When I was a kid I had a rabbit too,
his name was Franz.
在我小的时候，也有一只兔子，名叫弗兰兹
A birthday present from may father
是我父亲送我的生日礼物
Franz grew and grew, grew and grew,
only at Christmas Franz got very small again.
弗兰兹长呀长呀，只有到了圣诞节的时候，又变小了
My father said, Franz becomes small,
so that he freezes less.
我父亲说，弗兰兹变小了才不会被冻着
And I believed him. Until I understood
that every I ate Franz every christmas.
然后我相信他了，直到我明白每个圣诞节吃的就是弗兰兹
The story is made up right?
这故事是你编的吧？
Does she knows who you are?
她知道你是谁吗？
I know who you are.
我知道你是谁
The game is called: Who am I.
这游戏叫做：我是谁
The game sucks.
烂游戏
You don't need to play along.
你可以不参加
I want to be Lady Gaga.
我想当Lady Gaga
The game is different.
这游戏是另外玩法
The person to your left decides who you are
and he or she writes it on a piece of paper
坐在你左边的那个人可以决定你是谁
那个人将写一张纸条
and then stick it onto your forehead.
然后贴在你的额头
I am sorry but I can't do that.
抱歉，我办不到
Everyone will play along.
大家都要玩
Please stay here.
请留下
You can only ask questions that can be
answered with yes or no.
你可以提问，然后对方只能用“是”或“不是”来回答
[Jacko，应该是在Supertalent上表演的一只鹦鹉]
[Lady Gaga]
CUNT
[屄]
His, I don't get it.
我看不明白他那张
Sorry, but...
抱歉，不过…
You start, you have to ask who you are!
你先来，你来问大家你是谁
Am I evil?
我是坏蛋吗？
Good question.
好问题
Someone did evil to you but you also performed
evil by yourself, yes you are evil.
有人对你做了不好的事情，而你也做了糟糕的
没错，你是坏蛋
Am I sexy.
我性感吗？
It's not your turn until he gets a no.
直到才猜错了以后，才能轮到你
Have I killed Nicolas.
我有杀了尼库拉斯吗？
Do you want some more juice?
还要喝点果汁吗？
No, you haven't killed Nikolas.
没，你没有杀尼库拉斯
Now it's Anjas turn.
现在轮到安雅了
Mrs. Heine it's your turn.
海纳女士，该你了
Am I female?
我是女的？
For sure.
绝对的
That's insane.
简直胡闹
"There was an old spinster 0f street.
Who bellowed, My cunt is on fire!"
“一个老女人来到了街上
高声大叫，我的屄着火了”
So a fireman was found, brought his engine around,
and extinguished her burning desire.
“消防员带着工具赶来，拯救了欲火如焚的她”
Where is my son?
我儿子在哪里？
Nicolas was so scared, he peed himself.
He screamed mummy, mummy
尼库拉斯吓得尿了一裤子
他一直在哭喊：妈妈，妈妈
but he never said anything about daddy.
但他从没提到过爸爸
Stay, please!
请留在这儿！
Do you want to know who you are?
你想不想知道你是谁？
I thought it's my turn?
现在应该轮到我了吧？
I give you a hint.
我给你个提示
I want to ask something, too!
我也想要玩
Your parents wanted to tell you,
when you are old enough to understand.
你的父母本想等你长大了之后再告诉你的
But then you found your adoption certificate.
可你发现了自己的领养证
By accident or did you search for it.
偶然的…还是你特意寻找的
Did you sense that they are not your real parents?
你是不是感觉到他们不是你亲生父母？
Am I sexy?
我性感吗？
You are an anonymous birth.
Your biological parents are unknown.
你出生就是无名氏，你的生父母下落不明
This game sucks.
什么狗屎游戏
How does it fell
你的感觉如何？
when you don't know who you are,
and where you come from?
当你突然不知道自己是谁，从哪里来
When our own mother doesn't want you?
为什么自己的亲生母亲会把你抛弃？
Then he felt very bashful,
and tucked his head under his wing.
然后他开始难为情起来，把自己的头深埋到翅膀之下
He did not know what this was all about.
他自己不明白是为什么
He felt so very happy, but he wasn't at all proud,
for a good heart never grows proud.
他觉得很高兴，但不觉得骄傲
好心肠的人是不应该骄傲的
He thought about how he had been
persecuted and scorned,
他想到了自己过去是如何被欺负被嘲笑
and now he heard them all call him
the most beautiful of all beautiful birds.
而现在却听到大家都称赞他是所有美丽的鸟儿中最美的
The lilacs dipped their clusters
into the stream before him,
紫丁香在他面前也都弯腰把枝条伸到了水中
and the sun shone so warm and so heartening.
阳光是如此的温暖，如此的柔和
He rustled his feathers and held his slender neck high,
他扑扇了自己的翅膀，伸直了细长的脖子
as he cried out with full heart:
从内心发出响亮的叫声：
"I never dreamed there could be so much happiness,
when I was the ugly duckling."
“当我还是一只丑小鸭的时候
我做梦也没想到现在是如此幸福”
Beautiful ending.
结局真美
You forgot the good night kiss.
你忘记晚安吻了
The boy was handed in by an unknown person
in the baby flap of the children's hospital Albert Sabin.
这孩子是被人匿名送交给阿尔伯特·萨宾儿童医院的
The Infant was hypothermic and regarding
the umbilical cord at least 24 hours old.
婴儿当时体温过低，从脐带判断，已经出生24小时
He was treated medically and at the end of an eight,
week period given up for adoption.
医疗救治了八周之后，他被允许接受收养
The infant was 24 hours old, that means his birthday is
tomorrow not the day after
既然这样，那就是说，他的生日不是后天，而是明天
With Foundlings, the handover date is classified
as the official date of birth.
对于弃婴，往往会把他的接管日作为官方的出生日期
The real date is known solely by the mother
或许只有他的生母才知道其真实生日
Who gave the child his name?
谁给孩子起的名？
The adoptive parents.
养父母
Until then the infant remained nameless.
In the provisional certificate of birth,
在那个时候，婴儿还没有任何名字
在他的临时出生证上
is an X instead of the name.
姓名一栏填的是一个“X”
I didn't know you are a bastard.
我不知道你竟然是个私生子
Promise, that you never stand me up again,
like the funfair Will you promise me that?
向我保证，你再也不会像在游乐园那样放我鸽子了
能发誓吗？
Are you Gay?
你是同性恋？
Don't you like me?
不喜欢我？
Your tits are too small.
你连乳房都没有！
Asshole.
混蛋
Is it possible to find out,
who the mother of the child is?
能想办法找出来谁是这孩子的母亲吗？
With baby flaps, no chance,
everything is anonymous.
从接收弃婴的过程来看，没有任何信息
一切都是匿名的
But six months late; a young women appears in the
不过这里写了：六周之后，一个年轻女子出现在…
youth welfare office and claims
to be the mother of the child.
…青年福利局声称她是孩子的母亲
She wanted her child back,
然后想要回孩子
but the adoption was already completed.
可领养程序已经完成了，所以没成功
Did she try to contact her child?
她有尝试联系孩子吗？
She did, but the adoptive parents refused it.
Her name was included in the documents,
有，但养父母拒绝了
档案里应该有她的名字
nothing else could be done for hen
Her maiden name was Anja Wehling.
我也只能帮到你这里了
那女人的名字叫安雅·威林
Today she is called Heine.
现在改姓海纳
Hello Claudia, are you still there?
喂，克劳迪娅，你在听吗？
He did an internship in the youth wellfare office.
他在青年福利局做的社会实习
Leave me alone！
走开！
You and your wife,
how did you get to know one other
您跟您的爱人是怎么认识的？
At the university cafeteria ,
she didn't like her meal, I gave her mine.
在大学的餐厅，她不喜欢吃她的那份，我就把自己的给了她
You did not know anything about this?
您也对此毫不知情？
Five days ago,
we were just a normal family.
五天之前，我们还只是一个正常的家庭
Why didn't tell me about this!
为什么不告诉这件事？
You lied to me! 12 years!
你竟然骗了我十二年！
I'm your husband!
It's all about OUR child.
我是你丈夫！而这事关系到我们的孩子！
There's no sense...talk to me now!
没必要这样了…现在跟我谈谈！
What do you want?
你要干嘛？
I want to sleep in bed with mummy.
我想要跟我妈一起睡
Shit.
见鬼
I can't sleep.
我睡不着
Nobody has ever read to me.
没人试着来理解我
I heard about your father
My father died when I was al little kid, too.
我听说了你父亲的事，我父亲也在我很小的时候去世的
You can save your psycho stuff.
I don't know where the victim is.
你少跟我用心理疗法了
我不知道那个受害者在什么地方
Morning.
早
You look totally gay.
你看上去真基佬
And you have no clue
how to do it properly.
而且…你根本不知道该怎么弄
One line here.
这儿划一条
But not too strong,
your lashes are already quite dark.
不过不能太浓，你的睫毛已经很浓了
And now this.
还有这个
What's going on here?
这儿怎么回事？
I don't know.
我不知道
Surprise!
惊喜哟！
How nice that you were born,
we would have really missed you otherwise.
你的降临是多么美妙，我们是如此地期待
"How nice that we're all together;
we congratulate you, birthday child!"
我们在一起是最美好的事，祝贺你，小寿星
Happy Birthday.
生日快乐
Aren't you happy?
不高兴吗？
My birthday is tomorrow, not today.
我生日是明天，不是今天
Tomorrow?
明天？
Your birthday is today.
你是今天生日
Tomorrow.
明天
No, today.
不，今天
You have to blow out the candles.
你现在得吹蜡烛了
I am afraid I don't have a present for you,
cause I only just heard about it.
可惜我没能给你准备礼物，我总是最后才知道
But I have a present for you.
不过我有礼物给你
Here you are.
Your name is written on the present.
礼物上有写你的名字
I don't have a name.
我没有名字
I gave it to you, when you were born.
你出生的时候，我给你取了名的
Tell me where Nicolas is,
then I tell you your name.
告诉我尼库拉斯在哪，我就告诉你的名字
Tell me, where Nicolas is?
Then I will give you your name.
告诉我,尼库拉斯在哪里？
然后我就把你的名字给你
He is in the cellar of the water park.
他在水上乐园的地下室
Marienbad, where we were yesterday?
玛丽亚水世界，我们昨天去的那个？
Where is your telephone? Your telephone!
你们的电话呢？你们的电话！
Happy Birthday, Leon.
生日快乐，莱昂
I want you to go now.
Leave my house and never come back!
我希望你现在就走，离开我的屋子，再也不要回来！
I thought, we would celebrate together
我以为我们要一起欢庆的
You are arrested provisionally.
你被暂时拘押了
What? You can't do that, we are kids.
什么？你们不能这样的，我们还是孩子
As of today no longer
从今天起不再是了
Come on!
快点儿！
You promised that we celebrate his birthday today, all together
你保证过今天我们要一起欢庆生日的，大家一起！
You promised it!
你保证过的！
No, you promised it.
不行，你保证过的
But you promised it.
不要，你发过誓的
A promise is a promise!
保证过了就要做到！
Don't you want to say Good Bye at least?
你至少应该跟我告别一下吧？
Bye.
拜拜
A Real Good Bye!
要正儿八经的！
Bye.
再见
Hands Up!
举起手来！
Into the cellar you pussies!
到地下室去，臭女人！
Where is my child?
我的孩子在哪儿？
They didn't find him.
他们没找到他
WHERE IS MY CHILD?...WHERE IS MY CHILD?
...WHERE IS MY CHILD?
我的孩子在哪里？…
You fucked it up.
你把事情搞砸了
There is no way back for him now.
现在找不回他了
He will not do it.
他不会那么做的
Go and get a rest Mrs. Doctog
we can handle this from here.
去睡一觉吧，博士！这里交给我们来办
You look tiered.
你看上去太累了
Crazy, you actually look quite similar.
At least if you know it.
真神奇，你们俩个真的很像
至少，在知道真相后再比较
Look at the mouth,
it looks just like yours.
瞧他的嘴巴，就跟你的一样
Look the corners of the mouth!
瞧啊，嘴角这里！
You just can't see it, because of the... the...
你不愿意看，因为那叫什么来着……
Mathilda, I am trying to concentrate here.
玛蒂尔达，我现在需要集中注意
Sorry.
抱歉
You are scared like shit.
你害怕了
Of cause I am scared,
do I look like a psycho, or what?
当然害怕啊！难道我是杀人狂吗？
I can do it for you.
The cops will fuck you.
我可以替你办，警察会找你麻烦的
They will fuck me anyway.
他们反正会找我麻烦
Your mother loved his mouth more than yours.
跟你比起来，你妈妈更喜欢他的嘴巴
Although you have the same.
虽然你们俩的长一样
We don't have the same mouth.
我们的嘴巴不一样
Why not, you are brothers?
为什么不一样，你们是兄弟
Half brothers.
半个兄弟
Brothers, half brothers, fuck it!
You have the same mouth.
兄弟，半个兄弟，管它的！反正你们的嘴巴长一样
Mathilda, would you please wait outside?
玛蒂尔达，你能去外面等着吗？
Mathilda, would you please wait outside!
玛蒂尔达，麻烦你去外面等着！
I bet, you don't dare it.
我打赌你不敢杀他！
Give it back!
还给我！
It's mine, I stole it!
枪是我的，是我偷来的！
But the victim is mine.
但他这人属于我
Noisless: I'm sorry!
[对不起！]
Shit!
妈的！
The mother opens the flap from the outside
and puts her baby here into the bed.
妈妈在屋外打开传递箱，把她的孩子放进这床上
The bed detects that there is a child
and automatically warms up.
床马上会探测到有孩子躺上来了，就会自动加温
If the flap closes again, a silent alarm is set off
and we take care of the baby.
等传递箱再次合上
无声报警器就会启动，我们就会过来照料孩子
Really quite simple.
其实就这样简单
Do some mothers leave something for their children,
some kind of keepsake?
那些孩子的母亲会给她们的孩子留下什么东西吗？
…纪念物之类
Whatever we find next to the child
we keep in these envelopes.
不管我们在孩子身上发现什么，都会放在一个信封里保管
From the age of sixteen, the children have the right
to inspect these things.
等孩子到了十六岁，就可以接管这些东西
May I see the boy's envelope ?
我能看一下这个孩子的信封吗？
Do you know what's in there?
你知道里面是什么吗？
Sometimes a bad past is better than none.
有时候，一段糟糕的过往也强过什么都不留
Anna Heinzke, I baptise you in the name
of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit.
安娜·海因泽克，我以圣父，圣子以及圣灵的名义给予你洗礼
Amen.
阿门
The Lord bless you and keep you.
主会保佑你，伴随你
The Lord lift his countenance upon you,
and be gracious to you.
主会时刻支持你，给你仁慈
The Lord make his face to shine upon you
and give you peace.
主会永远善颜待你，给你安宁
Amen.
阿门
Come!
You are going to get your birthday present.
来…来拿你的生日礼物
Today is you birthday, we have to celebrate that.
今天是你的生日，我们肯定要庆祝一下
As long as the pussys are singing
this house is ours.
只要那些人的歌声没停，那这屋子就属于我们
Relax!
放轻松！
I swear, there is booze somewhere.
我发誓在这儿能找出酒来
To you!
敬你！
Here drink! Drink!
给，喝吧！喝呀！
It will make you relax.
会让你放松一点的
Drink!
喝吧！
This will be my birthday present.
这将是我给你的生日礼物
Do you like what you see?
喜欢你看到的吗？
Do you like me?
喜欢我吗？
Then show me!
那就让我看到！
Show me that you like me!
让我看到你喜欢我！
Happy Birthday, Leon.
生日快乐，莱昂
If I ask you for something, will you do it?
要是我让你做什么事，你会做吗？
No matter what it is?
不管是什么事？
Yes.
是的
Tomorrow at breakfast with mum and dad,
we will bring it to an end.
明天跟爸妈一起吃早饭，我们把事情解决掉
Leon?
莱昂？
I will bring the buns.
我会带面包来
We have this more often, sometimes stones,
vomit, deposit bottles...
经常会发生这样的事，有时候会有空瓶子
you can forget that,
the alarm has a delay of fifteen minutes,
这个你就不用想了，警报是推迟了十五分钟的
so that the mother stays anonymous.
这样的话，可以使那一方的人完全不被人发现
I am here.
我在这儿
Your father raped me
I am sorry, Mum.
是你爸爸强奸了我，对不起！
--妈妈
Had a nice day?
- 祝你愉快！
- 你也是，再见
Morning. Awake so early?
早呀！这么早就起了？
Yes.
恩
I would like to have four
of these normal buns.
唔…我想要四个这种普通的面包
Two custard tarts and...
another two of these cross, stuff.
这边的布丁派，要两个
然后…那边十字形的也是两个
You will talk now, and we keep out of it.
你们现在要相互谈一谈，我们在外面呆着
What do you want?
你想要让我怎么做？
Tell me who I am.
告诉我，我是谁
Did you know him?
你认识他吗？
你是不是认识他？
I was drunk. I just wanted to forget all that.
Three weeks laterl was pregnant.
我当时醉了，而且一心想忘记那事情
三周之后，发现自己怀孕了
Why didn't you abort me?
那为什么不去堕胎？
I was still covered by my parents' health insurance.
我那时候的医保还挂在父母的户头上
Bullshit.
胡扯
I was ashamed.
我羞愧万分
I thought it was all my fault
I shouldn't have drank so much.
我觉得都是自己的错，不该喝那么多的
And then?
然后呢？
What then? I got you.
什么然后？我就把你生了
Where?
哪里？
WHERE!
On the toilet.
厕所里
Alone on the toilet.
我一个人在厕所里
You were screaming all the time.
I did not know what to do?
你一直在哭，我不知道该怎么办
When the flap closed, I felt so relieved,
...like all this never happened.
当那个盖板合上之后，我觉得自己解脱了
…好像这一切从未发生过
Did you give Nicolas the breast?
你有给尼库拉斯喂过奶吗？
Did you suckle him?
有没有给他喂奶？
Yes.
有
Me too?
我也是？
No.
没
If you amputate someone's leg,
he can still feel it tickling, even years late:
要是你割断某人的腿，他还会感觉到痒，甚至几年后还会
When Nicolas is dead, where will it tickle you?
要是尼库拉斯死了，你会觉得哪里痒？
You didn't do it.
你没杀他
I know Nicolas is well.
我知道尼库拉斯没事
You want to see him?
It's no pretty sight.
你想看他？那可不是什么好景致
Let me alone.
别烦我！
I hate you.
我恨你
I am sorry.
对不起
I am so sorry.
真的对不起
Hello? We will now eat breakfast all together
你好？ 我们现在要一起吃早饭
Like a real family?
像真正的一家子
Hello? ...Hello?
喂？…有人吗？
I brought buns?
我带了面包来
Would you hand me the jam, please?
能把果酱拿给我吗？
Strawberry, please.
草莓味的
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh, the coffee is ready.
喔，咖啡煮好了
Milk?
要牛奶？
The weather is so beautiful today.
今天的天气真是不错呀
Shall we go for a walk?
要不要一起走走？
But you promised it.
怎么？你们说好了的
A promise is a promise.
保证过了就要做到！
You promised it. You can't do that.
你们保证了，但却不去做
A promise is a promise.
保证过了就要做到！
You always fool me. You always promise something
but you never keep it.
你们总是耍我，你们总是保证做一件事，却从不实现
A PROMISE IS A PROMISE!
保证过了就要做到！
Asshole!
混蛋！
Mum! Dad!
妈！爸！
Say, that you love me!
说你爱我！
Say it!
快说！
Leon?
莱昂？
Leon, I...I would like to see you...
莱昂，我…我想要…
I forgot Mathilda.
我忘记玛蒂尔达了
Me too.
我也是
Claudia...
克劳迪娅
are you all right?
你没事吧？
I have tried to reach you all the time.
我一直试着想联系你呢
I have to tell you something.
我有事要告诉你
Just come in for now.
先进来吧
如您喜欢德国电影，可关注微博微刊《德趣电影屋》
谢谢观赏
TLF字幕组欢迎你
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://t.sina.com.cn/tlfsubs
本片内容以及字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
字幕译制&校对：yourtear@TLF
影片压制：yourtear@TLF